<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on inkel</title>
    <link>https://inkel.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on inkel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 23:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inkel.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020: Day 3</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode2020-day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 23:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode2020-day3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on a roll! Day 1 was painful; in day 2 I did some improvements, and now day 3 was also solved in less than 2 hours!
I&amp;rsquo;m getting more familiar with Clojure, and the tools I use for this project: Leiningen, Emacs + CIDER. About the latter, I know I could be more efficient if I knew the commands better, but so far it is really useful and I&amp;rsquo;m not only learning tons but also in awe as to how well integrated this tool is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020: Day 2</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode2020-day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 14:47:52 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode2020-day2/</guid>
      <description>Funny how day 1 took me 4 days to solve but I was able to solve day 2 in just an hour. I guess the challenges are not strictly in a increasing order of complexity.
I also like that I think my Clojure programming style is getting better as the time passes, which in the end was my sole main objective.
Let’s see what day 3 lies ahead…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020: Day 1</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode2020-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 23:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode2020-day1/</guid>
      <description>I did it! I was finally to solve both Day 1 challenges in Clojure! And it only took me four days!
As said in my previous post one of the reasons why I&amp;rsquo;m participating in this years Advent of Code is because I want to learn Clojure, and while at times I felt frustrated because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the solution, I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I did. As with everything, in hindsight, the solution is obvious now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code 2020</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 10:31:18 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode-2020/</guid>
      <description>For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of the idea behind Advent of Code:
 …an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and skill levels that can be solved in any programming language you like.
 For a variety of reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve neglected participating in past editions, but this year I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to give it a try.
The biggest reason behind the decision to join this year was that for the longest time I had the desire to become proficient in any of the many LISP languages out there, particularly in Clojure, so I saw this as a chance to get more familiar with it, learn something more about it, and having fun while doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
