<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on inkel</title>
    <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on inkel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 23:30:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inkel.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020: Day 1</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode2020-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 23:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode2020-day1/</guid>
      <description>I did it! I was finally to solve both Day 1 challenges in Clojure! And it only took me four days!
As said in my previous post one of the reasons why I&amp;rsquo;m participating in this years Advent of Code is because I want to learn Clojure, and while at times I felt frustrated because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the solution, I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I did. As with everything, in hindsight, the solution is obvious now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inkelinks S01E02</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/inkelinks-s01e02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 11:00:08 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/inkelinks-s01e02/</guid>
      <description>Issue #2 of my newsletter was delivered today. I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying curating links and sharing them with friends! In case you missed it, here it is:
Yes! Welcome to a new issue of inkelinks. Last time it was the first one and of course I had a typo on the subject 😞 but all the links were working, so there’s that 💪🏽
In this issue you’ll find the regular links section plus a new Podcast Episode of the Week section where I’ll share a single link to an episode of the many podcasts that I listen to that I think has value for sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code 2020</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 10:31:18 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/adventofcode-2020/</guid>
      <description>For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of the idea behind Advent of Code:
 …an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and skill levels that can be solved in any programming language you like.
 For a variety of reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve neglected participating in past editions, but this year I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to give it a try.
The biggest reason behind the decision to join this year was that for the longest time I had the desire to become proficient in any of the many LISP languages out there, particularly in Clojure, so I saw this as a chance to get more familiar with it, learn something more about it, and having fun while doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inkelinks S01e01</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/inkelinks-s01e01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 15:39:04 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/inkelinks-s01e01/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the first episode of inkelinks! I hope the title is clear, but in case it doesn’t: this is a collection of links that I’ve found useful, fun, or interesting. I’m planning on releasing a new episode weekly on Fridays at around 14:00 UTC.
Links  Just a bunch of git stuff
I use Git extensively, and I’m quite aware of many of its internals and obscure commands, yet there’s always more things to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have a newsletter now: inkelinks</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 08:20:45 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/newsletter/</guid>
      <description>One thing I like to do is collect links for reading later, and let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, who hasn&amp;rsquo;t? I also usually share some interesting links with folks at work, where I made myself the fame as the links provider. So that got me thinking: why not creating a newsletter where I can share these links with a broader audience? So thank you to Buttondown I now have a newsletter for you: inkelinks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Am I a gamer now?</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/inkel-gamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:38:32 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/inkel-gamer/</guid>
      <description>For years I disliked playing games. Never before in my life I had a gaming console, and the last game I played from start to end was The Secret of Monkey Island. But a couple of years ago I decided to buy a PlayStation 4 and I&amp;rsquo;m extremely happy with that decision. The main reason was of course to start playing myself, but also to raise my kids in a house where gaming is &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uses This</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/uses-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 11:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/uses-this/</guid>
      <description>I always liked the interviews at Uses This, I find it really interesting knowing other people&amp;rsquo;s setups. And given that I do not foresee them interviewing me anytime soon, I went ahead and wrote my own.
Who are you, and what do you do? I&amp;rsquo;m Leandro López, better known on the Internet as inkel (all lowercase). I work as a software developer at Theorem, mostly doing backend programming but also dabbling in operations when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell grep</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/powershell-grep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 09:26:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/powershell-grep/</guid>
      <description>I kept forgetting how to perform the equivalent of grep(1) in PowerShell. The simple answer is Select-String. It is aliased to sls.
ipconfig | Select-String 192.168 I should probably add a permanent alias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I organize my work blocks</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/work-blocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/work-blocks/</guid>
      <description>After publishing my previous Working at Theorem: a typical workday article a co-worker asked me the following:
 Can you go into the details of what happens during those &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; blocks? Do you frequently check slack_email or only check them occasionally? Are you heads down for parts of the day? Do you have dedicated &amp;ldquo;help_review others&amp;rdquo; time or does it happen ad-hoc?
 This is an interesting question, so here are the answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating DNSimple ALIAS records to AWS Route53</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/dns-alias-to-route53/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:29:19 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/dns-alias-to-route53/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was tasked with migrating a DNS zone from DNSimple to AWS Route53. Overall it was pretty straightforward except when I had to migrate two ALIAS records. This is a special type of record that’s not part of the DNS specification, so there was no direct alternative.
Subdomain Say that you have a subdomain www.example.com that was using an ALIAS record pointing to www.example.net. This is by far the easiest to move, as it implies replacing the TXT record defining the alias for a CNAME.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working at Theorem: a typical day</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/typical-workday-at-theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 10:45:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/typical-workday-at-theorem/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve joined CitrusbyteTheorem 9 years ago, and since day 1 it was a fully remote experience. Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve learned lots about how to organize myself to approach each new workday although never gave much thought to it, until a few days ago, when while interviewing a candidate he asked what does a typical day at Theorem looks like. This post will try to address that question.
First and foremost, a disclaimer: by no means I speak on behalf of Theorem or the rest of my teammates; these are entirely my own experiences and do not reflect the reality of all the great people working at this company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI sort tricks</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/cli-sort-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/cli-sort-tricks/</guid>
      <description>If you are like me you might have used the sort(1) CLI utility more than once in your life. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve found a trick that I&amp;rsquo;ve never used before, and hopefully it will help someone else in the future.
Say that we have the following file to sort:
fpdy 01 08 wcfo juvi 01 02 ejan urbx 04 03 ckbw fkzq 01 08 myaz fjie 04 09 rhvo almv 04 02 adhs cuah 07 04 gbyt chok 09 06 nqwo emjd 01 04 ledx npto 02 10 nqsc Now, supposed that I wanted to sort first by the third column and then for the second one, then one would do sort -k 3 foo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Terraform Providers</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/testing-terraform-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 15:50:17 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/testing-terraform-providers/</guid>
      <description>If there&amp;rsquo;s one piece of technology I&amp;rsquo;ve come to love and depend upon these last years it definitely is Terraform. Sadly, the only provider that seems to be complete is the AWS provider, but others seems to be missing some useful resources or data sources. As an example, these past days at work I had to work with the Azure provider and found that I was really missing the ability to query Azure for Virtual Machine IDs, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a data source for this, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to import the virtual machines we&amp;rsquo;ve already created (insert long story reasons here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Protocol Support in Curl</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/proxy-protocol-support-in-curl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 08:49:02 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/proxy-protocol-support-in-curl/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve came across the following tweet the other day, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited:
https://t.co/P3BbFqx1ro CURLOPT_HAPROXYPROTOCOL: support the HAProxy PROXY protocol
Add --haproxy-protocol for the command line tool
Cl...
&amp;mdash; curl commits (@curlcommits) March 17, 2018  This is exciting to me as the work I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing in viaproxy had one caveat: testing it works was a bit convoluted, as I was doing by running an HAProxy instance with a custom configuration like the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using responsive font sizes</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/responsive-font-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 11:15:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/responsive-font-size/</guid>
      <description>Today Chad Ostrowski, a fellow engineer at Citrusbyte, shared an article he wrote: CSS pro tips: responsive font-sizes and when to use which units. After reading it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself and adapted some of the tips there to this site. It&amp;rsquo;s now much easier to maintain, I think, as I&amp;rsquo;ve removed all previous media queries, but I had to add one:
@media only screen and (min-device-width: 1200px) { html { font-size: calc(1em + 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From PEM to OpenSSH for usage in ~/.ssh/authorized_keys</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/pem-to-authorized-keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 15:51:51 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/pem-to-authorized-keys/</guid>
      <description>Say you have a private key in PEM format, and you want to use that key for SSH into another server, by adding an entry to your ~/.ssh/authorized_keys file with the public key of such PEM file. The following command will parse your PEM file and output the required RSA format used in authorized_keys:
ssh-keygen -y -f path/to/file.pem This will output a ssh-rsa AAAA… string that is safe to append to your ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lruc: a reverse cURL</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/reverse-curl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 10:24:08 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/reverse-curl/</guid>
      <description>Today Thorsten Ball asked a simple question on Twitter:
Does something like a reverse-curl exist? A tool that allows me to listen on a socket and return one HTTP response?
&amp;mdash; Thorsten Ball (@thorstenball) October 27, 2017  After a brief exchange of tweets, I said:
Or we could write one in Go 😺
&amp;mdash; Lean (inkel) (@inkel) October 27, 2017  Twenty minutes later lruc was born.
Oh wow! :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EC2 Key Pairs Fingerprinting</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/ec2-key-fingerprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 10:38:20 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/ec2-key-fingerprint/</guid>
      <description>Ever happened to you that you wanted to know which SSH key you need to connect to an AWS EC2 instance? I always found that the fingerprints don&amp;rsquo;t tell me much, espcially because I always forget how to compute the fingerprints. Good that I&amp;rsquo;m back to writing, so I&amp;rsquo;m dumping my memory here:
 if the key was generated by AWS, then use openssl pkcs8 -in path/to/key.pem -nocrypt -topk8 -outform DER | openssl sha1 -c if the key was generated using ssh-keygen then use openssl rsa -in path/to/private/key -pubout -outform DER | openssl md5 -c  Why does AWS uses one format and why SSH other?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Go package names</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/on-go-package-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 22:37:24 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/on-go-package-names/</guid>
      <description>Or why I renamed github.com/inkel/go-proxy-protocol to github.com/inkel/viaproxy. In my previous article I introduced a repository that hold the code to create net.Conn objects aware of the proxy protocol, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy with the name of the repository.
Package names are important in Go, and one aspect that we tend to overlook is that they actually are part of the calling signature when you want to use an export type or function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Protocol: what is it and how to use it with Go</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/proxy-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 14:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/proxy-protocol/</guid>
      <description>Today I became aware of the proxy protocol.
 The Proxy Protocol was designed to chain proxies / reverse-proxies without losing the client information.
 If you are proxying an HTTP(S) server, chances are that you have used the X-Forwarded-From header to keep the real remote address of the client making the request and not receving the proxy&amp;rsquo;s address instead. But this only works for HTTP(S): if you are proxying any other kind of TCP service, you are doomed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Commit</title>
      <link>https://inkel.github.io/posts/initial-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 15:47:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inkel.github.io/posts/initial-commit/</guid>
      <description>So here I am, once more, trying to have some sort of blog or journal. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to write about interesting pieces of code that I&amp;rsquo;ve written, problems I had to solve, books I&amp;rsquo;ve read (or dropped), et cetera. Don&amp;rsquo;t get your hopes too high, though, I&amp;rsquo;m lazy and tend to forget doing this kind of stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
